In this series, we're learning all about fall-blooming flower bulbs.
And some of my favorite flower bulbs are the Crocosmias, and within the crocosmias, the Lucifer.
I love Crocosmia Lucifer.
It's a native to South Africa, so it does very well in the Pacific Northwest, and it almost grows as a weed.
It really likes full, hot sun and good drainage, and hummingbirds love it.
I mean, once you've got a group of Crocosmia, you'll have thousands of hummingbirds in your yard.
And they're easy bulb to recognize and easy bulb to plant.
They look like a Hershey's Kiss candy, and there's a root side and bullseye side.
So the bullseye side goes up.
When in doubt, go sideways as another rule, and they multiply quickly.
But I found with all bulbs, they like to be in groups just like people do.
So if you put three in a triangle, it'll do much better than one by itself.
They'll do a lot more water, too.
I put 'em in some of the boggier areas in my yard and they've done well, too.
And it'll do well in drought conditions.
They're a plant that probably never needs to be watered and you'll never lose 'em.
Just a beautiful plant.
Sometimes they're called Montbretia.
So Montbretia is the same as a Crocosmia and these were hybridized, the Lucifer, in England back in 1966, and I like to think that was the same year I was born.
So they've been around for not a long time really in botanical history, but they're really a smash.
The next fall-blooming bulb that we'll talk about is Crocosmia Carmine Brilliant.